<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Cryptography on Dawn Yim's Blog</title><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/tags/cryptography/</link><description>Recent content in Cryptography on Dawn Yim's Blog</description><image><url>https://dawntyim.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 22:22:26 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dawntyim.github.io/tags/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Bitcoin Cryptography 4 - ECDSA (Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm)</title><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 22:22:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-4/</guid><description>Understanding Bitcoin Signature 4 - ECDSA (Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm) Digital Signature Algorithm Digital Signature Digital Signatures is based on asymmetric cryptography. Unlike symmetric cryptography that uses single key to encrypt and decrypt a message which is safer encryption, digital signature has to use asymmetric keys to enable ‘prove’ and ‘verify’ steps. We need a pair of public and private key so that the private key owner can prove that this message was encrypted by herself.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Bitcoin Cryptography 3 - Elliptic Curve</title><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 22:22:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-3/</guid><description>Understanding Bitcoin Signature 3 -Elliptic Curve Elliptic Curve The combination of elliptic curve and prime field arithmetic is utilized in various cryptographic applications due to the inherent difficulty of solving the discrete log problem.
Elliptic Curve on Real Numbers Elliptic curves have general form $y^2 = a x^3 + bx +c$. This is an example where a = 1, b = 1, c = 7 $y^2 = x^3 + x + 7$</description></item><item><title>Understanding Bitcoin Cryptography 2 - Prime Fields and Discrete Logarithm Problem</title><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 22:22:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-2/</guid><description>Understanding Bitcoin Signature 2 - Prime Fields and Discrete Logarithm Problem Prime Fields Bitcoin utilizes prime fields among finite fields due to their unique properties that make them well-suited for cryptographic applications. Specifically, a set of integers modulo a prime number forms a finite field with a prime number of elements. This finite field, known as a Galois field, is represented as $GF(p)$ or $\mathbb F_p^*$ or $\langle Z/pZ \rangle$.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Bitcoin Cryptography 1 - Intro and Finite Fields</title><link>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 22:22:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://dawntyim.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cryptography-1/</guid><description>Disclaimer: This is purely my (a complete layperson in Cryptography and mathematics) understanding of Bitcoin cryptography. There can be misinformation. Please correct me if anything’s incorrect!
Let’s start with the problem that Bitcoin is solving.
Bitcoin utilizes cryptography to ensure that only the true owner of a certain number of coins can prove ownership and that the public can verify this claim. This is achieved through the use of digital signature algorithms that employ the concept of public and private keys.</description></item></channel></rss>